How you doing, Keaton?
情r怎N,基D?
I can't feel my legs...
我的p腿失去了知X…
Keyser
P
Ready?
浜昧?
What time is it?
F在是什Nr候了?
It all started back in New York six weeks ago.
一切得牧星期前的~sf起
A truck loaded with stripped gun parts got jacked outside of Queens.
一vMd械部件的卡 在皇后^外被劫持了
The driver didn't see anyone, but someone fucked up.
那司C]目睹劫持者的相貌
He heard a voice. Sometimes that's all you need.
只到Ψ秸f的一句 有r候@些索就蛄
- Mr.McManus? - Christ! Don't you fucking guys ever sleep?
-克R{斯先生? -天！就他不能我睡安X?
- We have a warrant for your arrest. - Fuck you, pig.
-我被授⒛憔辛 -去死吧,i
- Who wants to know? - New York Police Department.
-是l找我? -我是~s市警局的
- Shit. - Freeze!
-死的 -不S樱
Hold it!
e樱
Sure you brought enough guys?
你真是如R大
It's quite simple:
@很:
A restaurant that changes with the taste without losing the overall aesthetic.
餐d的食物更Q口味, 而毫不适其整w的g感
In other words...
Q而言之…
...the atmosphere will not be painted on the walls.
…夥K不是由bI造的
- Let me give you an example-- - This I had to see for myself.
-我e例碚f-- -@得我自己砼
- I'm in a meeting. - Time for another one.
-我在公事 -有e的公事等你去
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
我斫榻B一下,@位是大l奎恩
Special Agent Kujan. US Customs.
美海P特e探T奎恩
These gentlemen are from the New York Police Department.
@孜皇羌~s市警局的
You look good. Better than I would have thought.
你馍不e,比我想像的要好
A small matter of a stolen truck loaded with guns.
不^是P於\被劫的小麻
Mr.Keaton?
基D 先生?
Will you excuse us for a moment?
原,我要失陪一下
We have some questions to ask you downtown. You'll be a while.
我得你回局e去, 事情不是三删渚驼f的清的
No. Please, sit down.
不,不.坐下
This is a small problem.
不^是些小事
Enjoy the meal. I'll talk to you later.
慢用.我t些再
It didn't make sense that I'd be there.
我根本]理由出F在那e
These guys were hard-core hijackers...
@些砘锉臼贺M盈的江洋大I
...but there I was.
…而我s也被列在其中
At that point, I wasn't scared.
不^我rK不害怕
I knew I hadn't done anything they could do me for.
我清楚自己是清白的, 他也不能拿我怎N
Besides, it was fun.
此外,@^程很有趣
I got to make like I was notorious.
我得把自己也成 是名狼藉的罪犯
You all know the drill.
你都知道程式
When your number is called, step forward and repeat the phrase you've been given.
被叫到的人就上前一步, 念出上的
Number 1, step forward.
一,上前
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
“把匙o我,混蛋”
Number 2, step forward.
二,上前
Gimme the fuckin' keys, you fuckin' cocksucker motherfucker!
“把他匙o我,你@死的混蛋！”
Knock it off. Get back. Number 3, step forward.
停,退後.三上前
- "Hand me the keys, you cocksucker." - In English, please.
-“把匙o我,混蛋” -v英Z
- Excuse me? - In English.
-你f什N? -v英Z
Hand me the fuckin' keys, you cocksucker. What the fuck?
“把匙o我,混蛋” @哪翰α?
Number 4, step forward.
四上前
It was bullshit. The whole rap was a setup.
@根本是胡,全都是栽E嫁
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
“把匙o我,混蛋”
It was the cops' fault.
全是l子的e
You don't put guys like that into a room together.
象@拥娜烁本不P在一起
Who knows what can happen?
l知道l生些什N?
"Hand me the keys you fucking cocksucker."
“把匙o我,混蛋”
This has really got to be embarrassing for you guys.
@事情一定你很^痛
They drilled us all night.
他了我整晚上
Someone was mad about that truck hijacking and the cops had nothing.
\被劫,有人暴跳如雷, 而l子s束手o策
They were hoping somebody would slip up and give them something.
所以希望有人撞到他口上
They knew we wouldn't fight, they knew how to lean on us.
他清楚我不能反抗, 他知道怎N向我施加毫
They've been doing it forever. Our rights went out the window.
他一直就是如此, 我的嗬早被`踏的o行
It was a violation. Disgraceful.
那直就是可u的C^人
They went after McManus first. Topnotch entry man.
他最先的是克R{斯, 他是打家劫舍的老手
What truck?
什N卡?
- The truck with the guns, fucko. - "Fucko"?
-\的卡,sN -“sN”?
He was a good guy. Crazy, though.
他是好人,只是有r有c狂
Wanna know what your pal Fenster told us?
想知道你的好兄弟范斯特是怎Nf的?
- Say who? - McManus.
-fl? -克R{斯
He told us another story.
他f的完全是另外一情r
Is that the one about the hooker with the dysentery?
是f那得了痢疾的妓女?
Fenster always worked with McManus. He was a real tight-ass.
范斯特是和克R{斯一起, 是油腔滑{的砘
But when it came to the job, he was right on. A smart man.
但是f到正事上, 他_算是明人
- What are you saying? - I said he'll flip you.
-你f什N? -我f他教你的
- He'll what? - Flip you. Flip you for real.
-他什N? -教你.狠狠的教你
- I'm shaking. Come on. - Okay.
-我怕O了,^m -好吧
- Answer my questions. - Can you hear me in the back?
-回答我的} -後面那位也的清?
Hello?
喂?
I want my lawyer.
我要律
I'm gonna have your fuckin' badge, cocksucker.
我要你@些死的l子G掉碗
Todd Hockney: good with explosives.
陶德霍克尼:爆破＜
Without a doubt, the one guy who didn't give a fuck about anybody.
毫o疑,@砘锊出u任何人
You guys don't have a fuckin' leg to stand on.
你根本]有立根
You think so, tough guy?
你以槭?
I can put you in Queens during the hijacking.
我能以在皇后^T劫的罪名起V你
Really?
是?
I live in Queens.
我就住在皇后^
Did you put that together yourself, Einstein?
所以你就@N把事情 在一起告我,垡蛩固?
You got a team of monkeys working full time on this?
你的那群猴子手下就是@Nk事的?
You know what happens if you do another turn in the joint?
知道你若是再投胎,怎?
I fuck your father in the shower, and have a snack.
我狂帜憷习
- Are you gonna charge me, dickhead? - I'll charge you when I'm ready.
-你想告我?白V -我Sr控告你
- With what? - You know damn well, dead man.
-{什N砀嫖? -你自己心e很清楚
But Keaton?
基D?
Keaton was the real prize for them for obvious reasons.
基D是他重c的目
It was your mistake, not mine.
犯e的是你,而不是我
Did you ever stop to ask me?
你到底完了]有?
I've been walking around with the same face, the same name.
我行不改姓,坐不改名
I'm a businessman.
是正商人
What's that? The restaurant business?
做什N生意?餐d生意?
No. From now on you're in the "getting fucked by us" business.
F在你要做的就是o我老招供
I'm gonna make you famous, cocksucker.
我把你K之以法的,混蛋
Like I said...
我已f了…
...it was your mistake
…犯e的是你
...not mine.
…而不是我
You charge me with this shit...
你要是胡y控V我
...and I'll beat it.
…我一定反V你
Okay?
明白?
Let's get back to the truck, asshole.
^mf卡的事吧,屁精
Really, somebody's got to do something about this shit.
真有人管管@事
They put me in holding every five minutes. So I did a little time.
他硬泳驼椅衣, 我真是受蛄
Does that mean I get railed every time a truck finds it's way gone?
y道f每Gv卡 就都得把我PM?
Fuck 'em.
他去死吧
Fenster, will you relax?
斯特,放c好?
- These guys don't have any probable cause. - You fuckin' right. No PC.
-他根本]有任何C -你f的,o{o
You're goddamn right. You do some time, never let you go.
真他f的太α 只要曾犯^小e,他就揪住你不放
They treat me like a criminal.
他我是罪犯般看待
- I'll end up a criminal. - You are a criminal.
-那N我t早也成罪犯 -你本砭褪亲锓
Why'd you got to go and do that?
致镎f的那N直接?
- I'm trying to make a point. - Why don't you make your point?
-我只是在做假O -做你的假O去吧
You're making me tired all over.
你我┩噶
Fuck it then.
去死吧
- I heard you were dead. - Yeah?
-我f你已死了 -是?
- You heard right. - Word I got is you hung up your spurs.
-你]有e -我f的是你已收手不至
- What's that all about? - What's this?
-@是怎N回事? -究竟怎Nf的?
Rumor has it Keaton's gone straight. I hear he's tapping Edie Finneran.
{言f基D已改^自新 和伊迪菲娜琳打的火
Who's that?
那是l?
She's a heavyweight criminal lawyer from uptown.
她是重量的刑事qo律
I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
她成了基D的票
How 'bout it, Keaton?
是,基D?
You a lawyer's wife?
你有律的R子?
What kind of retainer you giving her?
你是怎N勾上她的?
Do your friend a favor...tell him to keep quiet.
兔,叫他收吧
Dean Keaton...
迪恩基D…
Gone clean?
改^自新?
Say it ain't so.
我X得不可能
- Or was it you that hit that truck? - Mac, forget him.
-是f卡就是你的? -克,算了吧
Did you get to talk to your lawyer?
你和律^]有?
This whole thing was a shakedown.
整妒虑椴贿^是藉口
- What makes you say that? - How many times you been in a lineup?
-槭颤N@Nf? -你被指J^状?
It's always you and four dummies.
通常是你和四不相干的人
The PD are paying homeless guys $10 a head half the time.
警方找些流浪h, 每次o他十K
There's no way they'd line five felons in the same row.
他不同r把五罪犯放在一起
What's a voice lineup? Public defender could get you out of that.
-那音指J呢? -那o非是形式
- Why the hell was I strip searched? - It was the feds.
-槭颤N要找上我? -是邦{查局的砘
A truckload of guns gets snagged.
有v\被截下了
Customs comes down on NYPD for answers. They come up with us.
海P的人到~s警局要答案 於是他碚椅的麻
- They're clutching at straws. - I had a guy's finger up my ass.
-他把我成救命稻草 -我就@N被他玩
Is it Friday already?
F在是星期五了?
Yeah, lover boy.
是的,花花公子
You want a piece? Jump in. I'll love you.
想被人修理? 戆,我好好疼你的
So who in the goddamn piss hell stole our fucking truck?
那N究竟是他哪人渣的?
- What did you say? - Who stole the fucking truck?
-你f什N? -是l偷了那?
- I don't want to know. - Who asked you, workingman?
-我不想知道 -]人你,正人
Fuck who did it. What I want to know is, who's the gimp?
做@事的人去死吧 我F在想知道那跛子是什N人?
- He's okay. - Says you. How do I know that?
-]他的事 -全是你在f,我怎N知道?
What about it, pretzel man? What's your story?
怎N,拐_佬? ff你的故事吧
His name is Verbal.
他叫“口水先生”
Verbal Kint.
S伯肯特
- Verbal? - Yeah.
-“口水先生”? -
Roger, really. People say I talk too much.
真名是_,人人f我太多
I was going to tell you to shut up.
我正想叫你]嘴
- We met before, once or twice. - In County. I was in for fraud.
-我以前^一二次 -是在州局.我因樵p_罪被逮M了局子
You were in a lineup then, too. What happened?
我曾一同被指J 後砣绾瘟?
I walked. 90 days, suspended.
被判了90天,刑放
- So you did it. - All right, now look...
-你也不是好人 -好了,大家我f…
...we've all been put out by this whole thing, right?
…我都因@事被M
I figure we owe it to ourselves to salvage a little dignity.
我想我O法挽回c面子
Now, me and Fenster heard about a little job.
我和斯特f有渡意
Why don't you just calm down?
安o汉?
What do you care what he has to say?
他ff又怎N了?
I'm just talking here.
我不^S便ff
It seems to me like Mr.Hockney wants to hear it...
看砉肯尼先生 似乎想我要f什N…
...and I know Fenster's down.
…而我知道斯特亦有d趣
What about you, guy?
你呢?夥
I'm interested.
然有d趣
There. See?
看到]?
I'd like to exercise my right to free assembly.
我只想行使我的自由集
Why don't you just shut up?
]鹤觳恍?
You're missing the point.
你是不明白
No.
不
I don't want to hear anything from you.
我不想你f任何事
I don't care about your job.
我δ愕纳意]d趣
And...
此外…
...I want nothing to do with any of you.
…我不想和你有任何P
I beg your pardon, but you can all go to hell.
我很抱歉@Nf, 但你全都鬼去吧
Dean Keaton...
迪恩基D…
...gone the high road.
…想正做人
What is the world coming to?
@世界是怎N了?
Fuck him.
去他的
And that was how it started:
事情就是@N_始的:
Five of us brought in on a trumped-up charge...
我五因槟有的罪名
...to be leaned on by half-wits.
…被@些低能宏P了M
I really can't talk about it much here.
在@何艺娌荒芏嗾f
What the cops never figured out, and what I know now...
T警永h也想不到的是…
...was that these men would never break, never lie down.
…@些人永h不屈服
Never bend over for anybody.
永h不屈服於任何人
Anybody.
任何人都不行
- Who are you? - Agent Jack Baer, FBI.
-你是l? -FBI探T芸税
- How many dead? - 15 so far.
-死了多少人? -迄今橹拱lF15具企w
They're still pulling bodies out of the water.
在^m打扑下的企w
- Any survivors? - Two.
-有生者? -有
One guy's in County hospital, but he's in a coma.
一被送M了州立t院, 但他正在昏迷中
The DA has a second guy, a cripple from New York.
地方z察官ё吡肆硪砘, 一跛_的~s人
The chief wants this place sealed off.
上^下令封iF
If you have any questions, give him a call.
要是有e的}, 就o他吧
This is Dave Kujan. I'll be in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
我是奎恩,我去了洛杉, 星期二才回
If you need to reach me, contact Jeff Rabin of the San Pedro Police Department...
若有急事,可M }佩德_警署的芊蚶e…
...at extension 112. Have a nice day.
…找染112就可,祝你利
- Why can't I see him? - I told you...
-我槭颤N不能他? -我已f了…
...the DA came down here last night ready to arraign...
…地方z察官昨晚磉@e
...even before they moved him to County.
…涞人到了就_始提
Kint's lawyer shows up five minutes later...
然後^了五分, 肯特的律露面了…
...the DA comes out looking like the bogeyman smacked him around.
…地方z察官出 的r候像是蔫了的茄子
They take his statement, and they cut him a deal.
他o他了口供, Kc他_成fh
- Did they charge him with anything? - Weapons, misdemeanor 2.
-他以什N砥鹪V他? -非法持械,是p罪
What is that?
究竟是怎N回事?
I give the DA credit for getting that much, you understand?
@旱氖挛镆呀 全移交o地方z察官,明白?
Excuse me, sir.
一下
This whole thing has turned political. The mayor was here last night.
整妒虑殚_始有政治色彩 市L昨晚磉^了
The chief. This morning, the governor called, okay?
今天早上州L也曾打o^
I'm telling you, this guy is protected from up on high by the Prince of Darkness.
我告V你,@砘锏尼崤_很硬
- Take my word for it. - When does he post bail?
-得我f的吧 -他什Nr候可保外出?
- Maybe two hours, tops. - I want to see him.
-可能最多再^尚r -我想要他
- No. - I gotta see him.
-不行 -我一定得他
- No. I can't-- - You gotta do this for me.
-不,不行-- -你得臀
I came a long way for this.
我大老h砭褪榱诉@事
Dave, please.
M
Even if I let you talk to him, he won't talk to you.
就算我你他, 他也什N都不f的
He's paranoid about being recorded.
他X得是在被
- He knows the rooms are wired. - I quit.
-他知道室eM布CP -我戒了
This won't be an interrogation, just a friendly chat.
我不是他,只不^S便T了
- He won't go into the interrogation room. - Then someplace else.
-他不M室的 -那就去e的地方
Where?
哪e呢?
No, no.
不行,不行
If this was a dope deal, where's the dope? If it was a hit, who called it?
若@是毒品交易,那毒品呢? 如果是\,那又是l指使的?
I'm sure you have a host of wild theories to answer all these questions.
我相信@些} 在你心e已有了答案
- You know what I think. - That's crazy, and it doesn't even matter.
-你很清楚我的想法 -@直狂O了,而且也]什N意x
The guy's got total immunity. His story checks out.
@砘锔本不知情 他的背景也已查出砹
- He doesn't know what you want to know. - I don't think he does, not exactly.
-他]有你想知道的答案 -我知道他]有答案
But there's a lot more to his story, believe me.
但事情]有那N,相信我
I wanna know why 27 men died on that pier...
我想知道a^上那二十七人的死因
...for what looks to be $91 million worth of dope that wasn't there.
@事c九千一百f毒品有P 但F鼍拐也坏蕉酒
And above all, I want to be sure Dean Keaton's dead.
此外,我想_J迪恩基D的死
He's dead.
他_死了
Come on. Two hours. Just till he makes bail.
就o我尚r吧,到他被保就Y束
They're all dead.
他都死了
I don't care how tough you say Keaton was...
我才不在乎你f的 @基D有多害…
...nobody on that boat could've come out alive.
…船上]有生的人
- Is he talking? - He regained consciousness an hour ago.
-他能f? -他醒磉不到一小r
He spoke, not English, then he lapsed.
f了些,但不是英Z 然後就停下了
- Hungarian? - That might have been it.
-是匈牙利? -我不知道,也S是吧
- Most of them were Hungarians. - You gotta put this on.
-他大部分是匈牙利人 -你得把@穿上
Burn victims are very susceptible to infection.
病人很容易感染病菌
And, of course, there's no smoking.
有,那菏墙的
Keep your mask up. Please don't touch him.
戴上口罩,有e去碰他
Is he gonna die?
他死?
He's burned 60 percent of his body, broken ribs--
他全身有六成被 肋骨嗔--
Call security. Put a man on the door.
叫t院保安.人守在T口
- Is he dangerous? - Yes.
-他有危U? -
Do it.
去吧
Do it now.
快去
Joel? Baer. Down at LA County.
s耳?我是拜 穆迳即o你打淼
Look, the guy they pulled out of the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
他在a^找到的那人 叫阿科西卡瓦什
Yes, I'm sure.
是的,我明白
No, he's all fucked up.
不,他受了重
I can't hear you.
我不清
Will you shut up? I'm on the phone.
]鹤旌?我在打
No, not till I put a man on him.
不,直至我派人砜粗他
Send me someone who can speak Hungarian.
派f匈牙利Z的人
He's awake. He's talking like a Thai hooker.
他已醒了 @砘镎f就象泰妓女
Keyser Soze.
P W
- What? - Keyser Soze!
-什N? -P W！
No shit?
@是怎N了?
Call Dan Metzheiser over at Justice...
到法院去找丹曼厮固
...and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
…有海P的大l奎恩
Verbal, this is Agent Kujan from Customs.
S伯,@是海P的奎恩探T
Nice to meet you.
幸
He wants to ask you a few questions before you go.
他想在你x_前}
- What about? - About a Dean Keaton, mostly.
-什N}? -大部分是P於迪恩基D的
I'd like to start at the lineup back in New York.
但我想先由在~s的指J起
- Can I get some coffee? - In a while. Let's talk about the lineup.
-我能喝杯咖啡? -稍後再f吧,先ff指Jr的事
I'm really thirsty. I used to dehydrate as a kid.
我真的很口渴 我就象小孩子般的容易水
Once I got so bad my piss come out like snot.
有次我尿出的小便就象鼻涕一
- It was all thick and gooey-- - I'll get your fucking coffee.
-就是那N又庥终车-- -我去o你搞咖啡
Get me one, too, while you're at it.
便臀乙_一杯
That guy is tense.
那砘锾o了
Tension is a killer.
o足以使人致命
I used to be in a barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois.
我曾加入^在伊利Z州邵崎市 的一男四重唱M合
The baritone was this guy named Kip Diskin, big fat guy.
男中音就叫基普迪斯金, 是超大胖子
Like, orca fat. He was so stressed in the morning--
他每天早上都o的要命--
- You know we're trying to help you. - Sure, and I appreciate that.
-我F在是想湍 -xx,我很感激
And I wanna help you, Agent Kujan. I like cops.
我也想湍,奎恩探T 我喜gT警
I would've liked to have been a fed, but my CP--
我曾粝氤槁邦探T, 可是我的--
You're not tellin' us everything. I know you know something.
你]ξf 我知道你清楚一切
I told the DA everything I know.
我已Φ胤z察官全交待了
I know you like Keaton.
我知道你喜g基D
- I know you think he's a good man. - I know he was good.
-我明白你J樗是好人 -我知道他很好
He was a corrupt cop.
他曾是污的T警
Sure. 15 years ago, but he was a good thief.
,15年前的事了,他是好\
The cops wouldn't let him go legit.
T警不他的行楹戏化
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
迪恩基D是垃圾
Are you trying to get a rise out of me?
你想奈疑砩系玫近c什N?
- I just wanna hear your story. - It's all there.
-我只想你的故事 -已全f了
May I have a cigarette?
能抽支?
- According to your statement-- - I need a light.
-根你的口供-- -o火
According to your statement, you're a short-con operator...
根你的口供, 你只是小毛\…
...run-of-the-mill--
…不入流的--
...run-of-the-mill scams.
…不入流的_子
It's been suppressed. Anything in there is inadmissible.
@些口供已被封存了
I know. Sweet deal you have here. Total immunity.
我知道,你做了逗媒灰 你已被完全豁免
I do have the weapons charge. I'm lookin' at six whole months hard time.
我因非法持罪被起V 有六月的日子得熬
You know a dealer named Ruby Deemer?
JR一叫比迪莫的商人?
You know a religious guy named John Paul?
JR一叫s翰保_的教徒?
- You know Ruby's in Attica? - He didn't have my lawyer.
-知道阿提卡的比? -我和他]什N瓜葛
I know Ruby. He's big on respect.
我JR比,他很受人尊敬
He's a good friend of mine, likes me very much.
他是我的好朋友,也很喜g我
I know your testimony is sealed. Ruby's well connected.
我知你的C供已被封存 可比交[V
He's got lots of friends inside who do favors for him.
有S多朋友樗效力
What would he say if he found out you dropped his name to the DA?
若他知你把他的名字供o了 地方z察官,知道他怎N做?
- There's nothing there on Ruby. - I'll be sure to mention that to him.
-上面根本]提比的事 -可我@Nλf
Know what I've learned on the job? How to spot a murderer.
知道我倪@行W了什N? 就是如何J出词
Say you arrest three guys for the same killing.
假O捉了宗\案的三疑犯
Put them in jail overnight.
你把他P通宵
Next morning, whoever's sleeping is your man.
到了第二天早上, l要是睡著了,l就是词
If you're guilty, you know you're caught. You let your guard down.
如果你犯了罪,等到被捕 你的戒心就懈了
- You follow me? - No.
-明白? -不
Let me get to the point.
我_T山的直f
I'm smarter than you, and I'm gonna find out what I wanna know.
我比你明, 我查出我要知的事
I'll get it, whether you like it or not.
o你是否喜g,我都查出真相
I'm not a rat.
我也不是鼠
Thanks.
xx
When I was pickin' beans in Guatemala we used to make fresh coffee.
我曾在瓜地R拉L^ 咖啡豆磨的新r咖啡
Right off the trees, I mean. That was good.
直接渖险下的那N,好喝O了
- This is shit, but I'm in a police station. - Can we get started again?
-@味道糟透了,l我是在警察局e呢 -能^m?
What happened after the lineup?
指JY束後怎恿?
The desk sergeant was telling me he couldn't release you.
那值班的ξ艺f不能保你
Can you believe that? You weren't even charged.
你能相信?你甚至未被起V
Damn police.
死的T警
I wanna have pictures taken of your face.
我要o你的拍照
- I'll take them to the DA tomorrow. - Forget about it.
-明天就送到地方z察官那 -算了吧
I'll have this thing in front of a grand jury by Monday.
星期一我就把@事蟮酱笈F去
I don't want to talk about it, okay?
我不想再@事了
What did Fortier and Renault say?
弗提和雷Z那怎Nf?
They asked for more time to think about investing.
他需要多些rg考]投Y
Damn it.
死的
More time for what?
需要多些rg质颤N?
No matter how you cover my tracks they're still gonna find out about me.
o你怎N掩我的v史 他是查到我的底
Give me some credit.
相信我
I got you this far. Let's go to the grand jury.
我湍愠吻宓, 我一起去庭群献h
- This isn't gonna stop if we don't-- - It's never going to stop, period.
-如果不@,@事不停-- -@事永h不停
By next week, every investor in the city is gonna be walking away from us.
下星期所有投Y者都㈦x我
It's finished.
完了
I'm finished.
我氐淄炅
Don't give up on me now.
ep言放,基D
It's never gonna stop.
@事永h也不停
I love you.
我勰
They ruined me in there tonight.
他今晚Я宋
Do you hear me?
你到了?
What?
什N?
All right.
好了
Let's just go to my place.
去我家吧
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
明天再想@些┦
Let's go.
走吧
Fenster and McManus had a cagey proposition:
范斯特和克R{斯 有很好的:
A fast-jump, high-risk, long money.
X淼目,LU高,利也大
We all knew it could be done.
我都知道那行得通
The way I figured, to do it wrong meant killing.
我想那事若是k牧司偷⑷
To do it right took five men.
可要k好就要集R五人
Five men meant Keaton.
五人的PI就是基D
Keaton took convincing.
基D是令人信服的
New York's finest taxi service.
~sT警出租公司
Bullshit.
胡f
They don't operate anymore.
他早就已不至
McManus has a friend in the 14th precinct. They're coming out for one job, Thursday.
克R{斯有朋友在十四^ 他星期四收到了L
They're pickin' up a guy smuggling emeralds from South America.
他涫帐耙 哪戏亲咚石的砘
McManus already has a fence set up.
克R{斯已找到了NE人
- A fence? Who? - Some guy in California called Redfoot.
-NE人?是l? -是加州人,叫雷德福特
- I never heard of him. - You have to come.
-我奈绰f^@砘 -你一定要
- What's it to you whether I do it or not? - They don't know me. You do.
-我砼c不,c你何干? -他不JR我,只JR你
They won't take me unless you go.
除非你一起,否t他不信我
Look at me. I need this.
替我想想,我需要@PX
You're telling me you don't need this? Is this your place?
y道你就不需要?@是你家?
I'm not knocking you. You got a good scam going with this lawyer.
我不是在打裟 y道你就打算跟著@律吃?
Sorry.
Σ黄
It's okay.
算了
You say it's the real thing? That's cool.
你f得不e
You okay?
你]事吧?
I was out of line.
我已洗手不
But they're never gonna stop with us. You know that.
可他仍不放^我 你很明白@c
As clean as you get, they'll never let you go now.
即使象你般清白,他仍p著你
This way, we hit the cops where it hurts, and we get well in the meantime.
@N,既能ol子色看, 同r我也得了好
You sure you're okay?
你真的]事?
I'll be all right.
]事的
Look, I...
你看…
- ...sometimes get-- - Forget it.
-…我有r候-- -ef了
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
我今晚可能a血
So...
那N…
...how do they wanna do it?
…他想怎N下手?
McManus wants to go in shooting. I say no.
克R{斯想_⒔ 可我反
Fenster? Hockney?
斯特呢?哈肯尼呢?
They're pretty pissed off. They'll do anything.
他都豁出去了,什N都值某
I got a way to do it without killing anyone.
我有l不用⑷魏稳说穆
But like I say, they won't let me in without you.
可就象我f的, ]有你,他不我加入
$3 million?
三百f?
Maybe more.
也S更多
No killing.
不⑷
Not if we do it my way.
只要依我的方法行事便成
New York's finest taxi service was not your normal taxi service.
~sT警程公司是地下Q呼
It was a ring of corrupt cops in the NYPD that ran a high-profit racket...
那是~s污T警的生工具…
...driving smugglers and drug dealers all over the city.
…他接d走私客和毒
For $300 a mile, you got your own blue and white...
付上每公里三百元的rX, 你就有了私人的{白T警l
...and a police escort. They even had their own business cards.
他甚至溆忻片
After a while, somebody started asking questions, and the taxi service shut down.
]^多久,有人提出了| 而@程服找喔娼KY
Ever since then, Internal Affairs has been waiting to catch them in the act.
S後日部的人 ⑸姘傅娜硕季胁读
That's where we came in.
我就δ氢啡讼率
- So, how was the flight? - Fuckin' great.
-旅程愉快? -好的很
Will this get me to Staten Island?
用@能送我去史_Du?
Are you kiddin' me? This will get you to Cape Cod.
_什N玩笑? 就是把你送到科特角去也行
McManus came to us with the job. Fenster got the vans.
克R{斯去接生意, 斯特安排v
Hockney supplied the hardware.
哈肯尼提供械
I came through with how to do it so no one got killed.
我t想k法令各人不致被
But Keaton? Keaton put on the finishing touch.
基D? 基D把整妒绿砩献钺嵋还P
A little "fuck you" from the five of us to the NYPD.
稍有差e我五人⒙涞骄方手上
Watch this.
看著c
Careful.
小心
Come on, asshole!
真死
Holy shit!
天啊！
- Don't move, you fucker! - Drop it now, motherfucker!
-e,混蛋！ -把放下,sN！
Drop the fuckin' gun! Drop it!
把他的G掉！快G掉！
Don't fuckin' touch a fuckin' thing.
e他的碰任何|西
- What do you guys want? - Put your fuckin' thing away.
-你想要质颤N? -把那死的|西拿_
We're cops! Stupid assholes!
我是T警,蠢！
- Watch the glass! - Don't fuckin' move, motherfucker!
-小心玻璃！ -e,sN！
- You want a buckshot shampoo, chubby? - Shut up!
-想Lw子?胖子 -]嘴！
Fuck.
他的
'Afternoon, my little pork chops. Give me the shit.
下午好,兄弟.把|西o我
- Don't move! - Give him the shit!
-e樱 -把那|西o他！
Give him the fuckin' thing!
快把那死的|西o他！
Hurry up! Come on!
快c！拿恚
- Now the money! - There's no money.
-有X -]有X了
- Give me the money now! - There's no fuckin' money.
-把X交出恚 -根本]有X
Give him the fuckin' money!
把Xo他！
- Do it! Give him the money! - Give me the money!
-快！把Xo他！ -把Xo我！
- Give him the money! - Hurry up!
-把Xo他！ -快c！
You know who the fuck I am?
你知道我是l?
You people know who the fuck I am? Fuck!
你@些砘镏道我是l? 他的！
We do now, jerk-off.
F在知道了
Cocksucker.
混蛋
Wait a minute. What's that?
等等,那算什N?
What the fuck?
@到底算什N?
Holy shit!
天啊！
Go!
走！
Keaton made an anonymous phone call.
基D打了匿名
The press was on the scene before the police were.
新界cT警一起抵_F
Strausz and Rizzi were indicted three days later.
三日後,史道及瑞被控罪
Within a few weeks, 50 more cops went down with them.
不到星期, 又有50多T警亦被控罪
Everybody got it right in the ass, from the chief on down.
@案子窟B很V, 直到挖出了他的^X
It was beautiful.
值钠亮O了
I owe you $2.50.
我欠你K半
Dr.Keaton.
基D博士
- There's more here than I thought. - When's the fence coming?
-比我想的要多 -NE的砘锸颤Nr候到?
Redfoot never comes to see me. I always go to see him.
雷德福特不主硪我 一般都是我去找他
In California?
在加州?
Yes, Verbal, in California. Fenster and I--
是的,S伯,在加州 斯特和我--
Wait, hold the fuckin' phone. You and Fenster? No.
等等,先收 你和斯特?不行
- You fuckin' kiddin' me? - So then, who's gonna go?
-你想耍我? -那N派l去?
We all go.
我一起去
What's your fuckin' problem, man?
你有什N}?夥
My problem, is you and Fenster honeymooning in California...
我的}就是, 你和斯特在加州逍b快活
...while the rest of us are sittin' here holding our dicks.
…而把我甩在@e提心吊
The job's over.
已完事了
Cool it.
冷oc
LA's a good place to lay low for a while.
洛杉是p的好地方
You wanna dance?
想要跳舞?
Ladies.
B
I would like to propose a toast.
我提h大家忠槐
There you go.
敬你的
To Mr.Verbal...
樽阒嵌嘀\的…
...the man with the plan.
…“口水先生”而
We're gonna miss the flight.
我e^班C的
Don't do this. Send her a note. Something.
e傻等了, o她留便l就行了
I said we'll make it.
我f了淼眉暗
We're gonna miss the plane.
我快要`C了
She'll understand.
她理解的
That's heartwarming. Really.
那真的很感人
I'm weepy.
我有c想哭了
You wanna wait outside?
到外面去等好?
You guys wanted to know what happened. I'm telling you.
是你想知道l生的事 我正和你f
Come on, Verbal.
^m吧,S伯
Who do you think you're talkin' to? You expect me to believe that he retired?
你以槲沂钦l? 你要我相信他真洗手不?
For a woman?
就榱女人?
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
胡扯,基D是在利用她
- He loved her. - Sure.
-他鬯 -]e
I'm supposed to believe that hitting the taxi service wasn't his idea.
我很y相信u粲程 不是他的主意
- It was all Fenster and McManus. - Keaton was a cop for four years.
是范斯特和克R{斯提出的 -基D做了四年的T警
Who else would know better?
l比他知道的更清楚?
- That job had his name on it. - Edie had him turned around.
-他已是臭名hP -但伊迪使他全改了
Let me tell you something.
我@N告V你吧
I know Dean Keaton.
我t解迪恩基D
I've been investigating him for the past three years.
^去四年我一直在{查他
The guy I know was a cold-blooded bastard.
我知道@砘锸冷血的sN
IAD indicted him on three counts of murder before he was kicked off the force.
警_除他前 已有三次被控\
Don't sell me the hooker with a heart of gold.
e告V我妓女也有w金子般的心
You got him all wrong.
你完全`了他
Do I?
是?
Dean Keaton was under indictment seven times while he was on the force.
迪恩基D在警r 已有七次被控罪的
In every case, witnesses either reversed their testimony...
每次不是C人翻供
...or died before they could testify.
…就是在出庭前就被值
When they finally did nail him for fraud, he spent five years in Sing Sing.
等到K於能把他入罪, K送M州立新新OzP上五年
He killed three prisoners inside.
他s在e面⒘巳囚犯
Of course, I can't prove this...
然,我不能C明此事
...but I can't prove the best part either.
…但我亦不能C明他]有做
Dean Keaton was dead.
迪恩基D死^一次
Did you know that?
你知道那故事?
He died in a fire two years ago, during an investigation into the murder...
赡昵八在{查一宗…
...of a witness who was going to testify against him.
…C人被案r葬身火海
Two people saw Dean Keaton walk into a warehouse he owned...just before it blew up.
有扇艘到迪恩基D 在爆炸前M了}
They said he went in to check a leaking gas main.
他f他去z查煤馐欠漏
It blew up and took all of Dean Keaton with it.
Y果迪恩基D就此葬身火海
Within three months of the explosion, the two witnesses, they were dead.
爆炸l生三月後, 那目羧艘菜懒
One killed himself in his car.
一是在茸
The other fell down an open elevator shaft.
另一碾梯跌下而死
Let's get this show on the road.
我快_始吧
This is not what we discussed. There are too many--
我f好了不能@ F在有太多--
I promise we'll be out before he blows his porch light.
我答他死之前我x_
- I have a noon meeting. - Five minutes.
-我中午有要_ -只能待五分
Everyone calm down, all right?
好,所有人要冷oc
I want you to ask this man about the shootout in the harbor.
我要你他a^鸬氖
- He says they were buying-- - Dope. We know.
-他f他在I-- -是毒品,我知道
He doesn't know what they were buying, but not dope.
他不知道他要I什N, 但肯定不是毒品
- People. - What?
-是人 -什N?
He needs guarantees...
他需要保C…
- What is he talking about, guarantees? - He says his life is in danger.
-他f什N?保C? -他f他有生命危U
He saw the Devil. Looked him in the eye.
他到有只魔鬼在望著他
- I'm on my way. - No, wait a minute.
-我得走了 -不,再等等
Ask him to tell him what he told me...
他那他f^的…
...about the Devil.
…那魔鬼的事
Who's the Devil?
魔鬼是l?
Keyser Soze.
P W
Keyser Soze?
P W?
He was in the harbor, killing many men.
他在a^上⒘嗽S多人
He saw Keyser Soze?
他看了P W?
- He saw his face. - All right.
-他看到了他的 -好,好
Tell him to tell her what he looks like.
他告V她 那人的L相是怎拥
Describe him.
形容出
Six weeks ago, I get an anonymous phone call...
六星期前,我接到匿名…
...telling me I can find Keaton eating at Mondino's, and there he is.
…f能在R甸奴餐d找到基D Y果他_在
Because he never profited from his alleged death...
由於他畏Q已死K]什N利益
...and we convicted someone else of the murder we tried to pin on him...
…也因槲已找到真正的词
...we had to let him go.
…所以只得他走
He was dead just long enough for the murder rap to blow over.
他畏Q死去的rg已蜷L 足以平息那宗\案的影
And then he had lunch.
於是他就_始露面吃午餐了
I don't know about that.
我δ且o所知
I don't think you do, but you say you saw Keaton die.
我不J槟阒道什N, 可你f看基D死了
I think you're covering his ass, and he's still out there.
我在想你可能是樗掩, 而他仍藏身在某
I think he's behind that circus at the harbor.
我J樗就是a^鸬哪会嶂魇
My bet is he's using you because you're stupid and think he's your friend.
他利用你是因槟惚 而且J樽约菏撬的朋友
You tell me he's dead, so be it.
你ξ艺f他已死,就他死了
I wanna be sure before I go back to New York.
我只想在回~s前_定他已死
He wasn't behind anything. It was the lawyer.
他根本不是幕後主使, 那是律
What lawyer?
什N律?
Back when I was in that barbershop quartet--
在我在男四重唱Mr--
You don't think I know you held out on the DA?
你以槲也恢道 你[m了地方z察官?
What did you leave out?
你到底[m了什N?
I could be on the phone to Ruby in 10 minutes.
我能在十分染驼业紧比
- The DA gave me immunity. - Not from me.
-地方z察官已⑽一砻 -我]有
You get no immunity from me, you piece of shit.
我K]有豁免你,混蛋
Every criminal I have put in prison, every cop that owes me a favor...
我⑺有罪犯P在z中, 每T警都感激我…
...every creep and scumbag that walks the street...
…所有犯罪的大小角色…
...will know the name of Verbal Kint. You talk to me...
…都知道S伯肯特的大名…
...or that precious immunity they grant you...
…你o我老交待, 不然你@得的珍F豁免唷
...won't be worth the paper the contract put out on your life is printed on.
…^不交到你手上
There was a lawyer.
有律
Kobayashi.
叫彀脱潘够
- Is he the one that killed Keaton? - No, but I'm sure Keaton is dead.
-就是他⒘嘶D? -不是,但我肯定基D已死了
Convince me.
f服我相信
Tell me every last detail.
把情原原本本f出
We arrived in Los Angeles and met McManus' fence, Redfoot.
我抵_洛杉去 克R{斯的NE人,雷德福特
He had a good reputation. Seemed like a good guy.
他有著不e的名, 似乎是好人
- Still, we should have known better. - How you doing?
-可我得多t解 -好?
- Good. You? - Not bad. Can't complain.
-好.你呢? -也不,RR虎虎了
How's it going, Fenster?
你怎N,斯特?
Don't need to open it, right?
不需要打_吧?
You must be Keaton.
你一定是基D
Redfoot, Dean Keaton.
@是雷德福特,@是迪恩基D
- Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint. - Verbal, the man with the plan.
-陶德霍克尼,有S伯肯特. -\多多的S伯?
You interested in more work?
有d趣再忠话?
- We're always looking for extra work. - We're on vacation.
-我一直在找活 -我在休假
That's too bad.
那真可惜
I got a ton of work and no good people.
我有大堆的活, 可惜就是找不到好手
- Not like you guys. - What's the job?
-要象你@般身手的 -有什N活?
There's this jeweler out of Texas named Saul.
有牡驴怂_斯州淼闹商 叫索
He rents a suite in some downtown hotel.
他在市中心的酒店租了g套房
He does free appraisals. Sometimes he buys, sometimes he doesn't.
他免M槿髓b定r格 有rI,有rs不I
The word is, he carries around a lot of cash.
而言之,他手上有大PF金
So I figure, I keep the merchandise, you keep the green.
我想的就是, 我可以收,而你拿Fn
- Simple. - What about security?
-蔚暮 -安全方面如何?
A couple of bodyguards. Nothing you couldn't handle.
有保S 你完全可以搞定
Give me time to check it out?
可以o我rg考]?
I expect nothing less from you, man.
我聿δ闶望,兄弟
Good to see you. We'll call you.
很高d到你,M吧
Enjoy LA. Get yourself laid.
好好的在洛杉享受
A friend in New York tells me that you knew Spook Hollis.
有~s朋友告V我 你JR斯伯克荷利
The way I hear it, you did time with ol' Spook.
我f你曾和他一同服^刑
A good man, wasn't he?
他是好人
I used to run dope for him.
我以前曾樗^毒
Too bad he got shivved.
可惜炝
I shivved him.
是我把他值舻
Better you hear it from me now than from somebody else later.
@事直接由我告V你 比以後e人鹘o你好
I appreciate that.
xx你告V我
But just out of curiosity...
恕我好奇…
...was it business or personal?
@粹是公事,抑或私人}?
A bit of both.
烧叨际
Like I said...
就如我f的…
...you give me a call if you're interested.
…若你有d趣,可o我
Is there a problem?
有}?
One job.
只忠淮
That was the deal.
就是@
One job?
只忠淮?
That's a good one.
f的真好
Keaton fought it as best he could, but a man can't change what he is.
基D已竭M所能, 但人不能改身份
He can convince anyone he's someone else, but never himself.
他可θ苏f他另一身份, 但始K不能[自己
It took one day with McManus nagging, and we went back to work.
克R{斯整天都在Z叨, 於是我又只乇拘
I get out of my car, and the thing is wrecked.
於是我下了,那事全被了
I look in the backseat of the other car, and this woman's totally naked.
我向另外那v的後座看去 那女人缀跞光了
- I'm laughin' so hard I can't breathe. - Get in the car, Saul.
-我笑到快透不^ -上吧,索
- Freeze, motherfucker! - Stay right there!
-e,混蛋！ -站著e樱
Gimme the case. Give me the fuckin' case!
把公文箱o我 快把公文箱o我！
Give me the fuckin' case. I'm tellin' you for the last time.
快把公文箱o我 我v最後一次…
Give me the fuckin' case!
快把公文箱o我！
- Come on! - Don't move!
-^恚 -e樱
Hand over the case.
把箱子f出
Hand over the fuckin' case.
o我把箱子f出
Come on, let's go!
好了,走吧！
- Come on! - Bad day. Fuck it.
-快！ -今天真倒楣
Let's go!
快走了！
Fuck.
混蛋
- Looks like a lot of china to me. - Shit.
-就像是堆泥巴般毫or值 -真死
Guys, come on.
夥,砹
- What are you doin'? - I'm gonna kill him.
-你想质颤N? -我要⒘四砘
We did it your way, now we'll do it mine.
我已按你的方式e了回, F在我的
- You gonna kill him? - I'll deal with him.
-你要⑺? -我去和他
- You'd better, or I'm gonna. - Shut up.
-你最好和他好好 -]嘴
What am I supposed to do with that?
你叫我拿@|西有什N用?
Feed it to the gimp. Ease his pain. I don't know what that is.
拿砦鼓酋俗影,能退止痛 我也Υ瞬恢情
- What do you mean? - I don't know.
-什N意思? -我K不知情
I got thrown this job by some lawyer.
是律叫我@N做的
Who?
是l?
I don't know. Some limey.
我不知道,是英佬
He's a middleman for somebody. He doesn't say, I don't ask.
他也只是中g人 他不f的,我也不
- You're fuckin' full of shit! - Fuck you.
-你真是混蛋！ -去死吧！
- Fuck you. - Listen to me.
-你才去死吧！ -我f
We wanna meet him, okay?
我想要他
That's funny.
那真巧了
He called me last night. He says he wants to meet you guys.
昨晚他o我,也f想要你
Okay, we'll meet him.
那好,我去他
- I'll call you. - Good. Let's go.
-我o你 -好,我走
I don't like it. Wait a minute. One more thing, tough guy:
我不想@,等等 有件事,男∽:
Any more surprises, and I'm gonna kill you.
再玩什N花,我做了你
You're such a tough guy. But do me a favor, all right?
就臀忙好?
Get the fuck off my dick.
快在我面前消失
No!
不要！
Put a leash on that puppy.
好好管教管教那小子
It's an awful shame about Saul gettin' whacked.
索被⒄媸窃愀馔噶
Cops'll be lookin' for the guys who did it.
T警在追凶徒
Sooner or later, they're gonna come around askin' me.
他t早我
You have a sweet night, ladies.
祝你晚安,小姐
Fuck you.
去死吧
- So this lawyer-- - Kobayashi.
-那N@律-- -彀脱潘够
- Came from Redfoot. - Right.
-是雷德福特引淼? -
And why leave this out when you talked to the DA?
和地方z察官f的r候楹温┝诉@段?
Dave, someone to see you.
大l,有人找你
I've been looking all over for you.
我M世界的在找你
You still after that coke that took a walk out of that bloodbath yesterday?
仍在追查昨晚a^大屠⒌亩酒?
You can stop looking. There was no coke.
不用查了,根本]有毒品
I've been in LA County talking to a guy they pulled out of a drainpipe...
我去州立t院找了 那南滤道救上的…
...yesterday after the shootout.
…昨晚疳岬存者
He came to this morning, he started talking.
今早他K醒了,Kf了些事情
He's part of a Hungarian mob. They dealt with gwats from Argentina.
他是匈牙利匪偷囊T 他A浜桶⒏廷h徒交易
He says it was definitely not a dope deal.
他f@事c毒品交易oP
- But there were-- - We know. But he says no on the dope.
-但是-- -我知道.可他f@事c毒品oP
This Hungarian tells me they were pulling stumps for Turkey the next day.
@匈牙利人告V我 @班人翌日便要去土耳其
They had no time for that kind of product, and no means to move it.
他]rg去那批 亦]考]搬它
- What's the money for? - He didn't know.
-那X是做什N的? -他不知道
No one doing the deal knew except for a few key people.
除了PI人物外o人知
They were all very hush about it, he says.
他f那些人都守口如瓶
- Whatever it was, it was very sensitive. - I don't get it.
-o那是什N,都窟B重大 -我不太明白
You got the cripple in there from New York?
你到了那跛_的~s人?
Did he mention Keyser Soze?
他有提到P W]?
Who?
l?
Just bear with me here.
原我的打_
- Who's Keyser Soze? - Fuck!
-l是P W? -去死吧！
We've been goin' over this for an hour and a half.
我已了一半小r
What we need to do is find Redfoot and get the hell out of here now.
我只需要做了雷德福特 然後x_@死的地方就行
What we need to do is think.
我需要先思考周全
Think back.
再想想
Somebody with power...
有人有能力…
...somebody capable of tracking us from New York to LA.
…有人能募~s 一直追查我到@e
- What the hell are we doing here? - We're waiting.
-那我在@鹤鍪颤N? -我得等待
- Sit down. - No. I'm hot, and I'm fuckin' bored.
-坐下 -不用了,我火獯笾,他┩噶
Mr.Hockney, do stay.
哈肯尼先生,停下
Mr.Keaton.
基D先生
Mr.Fenster I recognize from his mug shots...
范斯特先生,我pR他的法…
...as well as Mr.McManus.
…就和克R{斯的一雍
I can only assume that you are Mr.Kint, the gentleman who disposed of Saul Berg.
你一定就是肯特先生, 那位值羲伯格的人
My employer sends his gratitude, a most unexpected benefit.
我的雇主致上他的感x, 和一份意想不到的Y物
I am Mr.Kobayashi.
我就是彀脱潘够先生
I have been asked by my employer to bring a proposal to you gentlemen.
我的雇主要我Х萁ㄗh
- What do you want? - My employer requires your services.
-你想怎? -我雇主想你樗效
One job, one day's work. Very dangerous.
任罩坏靡,工作一天 但相危U
He does not expect all of you to live. But those of you who do...
他]A你全部能活命…
...will have $91 million to divide between you in any way you see fit.
…但能活命的可⒛蔷徘б话偃f分了
Who's your boss?
l是你的老?
I work for Keyser Soze.
我P W做事
Who's Keyser Soze?
l是P W?
Judging by the sudden change in mood...
你太情w化了,肯特先生
...I feel sure the rest of your associates can tell you.
…我想你的合夥人也是@NJ榈
I come with an offer directly from Mr.Soze.
我代 W先生向你提出建h
- An order, actually. - What do you mean, "an order"?
-H上是命令 -什N叫做“命令”?
In 1981, you participated in the hijacking of a truck in Buffalo, New York.
1981年,你在~s巴弗洛^T劫
The cargo was raw steel, steel which belonged to Mr.Soze...
上是原材料 @批材料原凫 W先生…
...and which was destined for Pakistan to be used in a nuclear reactor.
…本送到巴基斯坦作核反t
A most profitable violation of UN Regulations.
那是`反合l例的大生意
You had no way of knowing this...
你根本不知此事,基D先生
...because the fellow shipping the steel was working for Soze...
因 W先生承\的人
...without his knowledge.
也根本毫不知情
Earlier this year, Mr.Fenster and Mr.McManus...
今年初,范斯特先生 c克R{斯先生…
...hijacked a two-prop cargo flight out of Newark airport.
在~A克C鲵T劫了架p座C
The plane was carrying gold and platinum wiring also set for Pakistan.
C上d有S金和白金
Two months ago, Mr.Hockney stole a truck...
月前,哈肯尼先生偷了…
...carrying gun parts through Queens.
…途皇后^的bd械零件的
Gun parts which were set to be destroyed by the state of New York.
手零件本要由~s州政府O督N
They were to be lost in a way station and rerouted to Belfast.
但在法斯特DCr就失了
Again, Mr.Soze using pawns who had no knowledge.
同拥, W先生利用不知情的人
Which brings us to Mr.Kint.
@游就找到了肯特先生
Nine months ago, one of Mr.Soze's...
九月前, W先生的…
...less than intelligent couriers was taken in a complicated confidence scam...
…一不算明的手下
...by a cripple.
…被一跛子所_
He was relieved of $62,000.
他被_去了六f二千元
Now, it has taken us some time to find you.
花了很Lrg, 我才找R你
Our intention was to approach you after your apprehension in New York.
我想你在~s落W後再找你
You set up the lineup.
是你安排的指J^程
Yes. You were not to be released until I had come to see you.
是的.我未到,你是不被放
It seems Mr.Keaton's attorney, Miss Finneran...
看砘D先生的律菲娜琳小姐
...was a little too effective in expediting his release.
…做事很有效率
Holding the rest of you became a moot point.
拘留你其N各人成檎c
- What about Redfoot? - Mr.Redfoot knew nothing.
-那雷德福特呢? -雷德福特先生也一o所知
Mr.Soze rarely works with the same people for long...
W先生很少L久 用同一批人工作
...and they never know who they're working for.
而工作的人亦不知檎l效
One cannot be betrayed if one has no people.
若]有手下,便不被出u
So, why are you telling us?
你槭颤N告V我?
Because you have stolen from Mr.Soze, Mr.Fenster.
因你偷了 W先生的|西
All of you.
你所有人
That you did not know it is the only reason you're still alive.
由於你不知道偷了他的|西 故此你尚生存
He feels you owe him. You will repay your debt.
他X得是你欠了他 你要o他
Fuck the debt, and fuck you. How do we know you work for Soze?
去他的,你去死吧 我怎知你是 W工作?
I don't think that is very relevant.
哈肯尼先生,你所f的K不切}
All five of you are responsible for the murder of Saul Berg...
你五c索伯格…
...and his bodyguards.
…及其保S的死有P
Mr.Redfoot can testify to your involvement.
雷德福特先生可C明此事
- What's your point? - The offer is this, gentlemen:
-你想f什N? -建h是@拥:
Mr.Soze's primary interest...
W先生一直Χ酒飞意
...is narcotics.
…很有d趣
He has been competing, shall we say...with a group of Argentineans for several years.
他c阿根廷h的曛久
Competing with Mr.Soze has taken its toll.
c W先生抗的人 已L到了教
These Argentineans are negotiating the sale...
他三天前商好了一宗…
...of $91 million in cocaine in three days time.
…九千一百f元的可卡因Iu
Needless to say, this purchase will revitalize...the diminishing strength of their organization.
不用f,@P交易 重新突钏的M
Mr.Soze would like you to stop the deal.
W先生想你制止@次Iu
If you choose, you may wait until after the buy.
你可等交易完成後才邮
Whatever money changes hands is yours.
他交易的X全凫赌
Mr.Soze would like you to get to the boat and destroy the cocaine onboard.
W先生想你在船上缈煽ㄒ
And then you will be free of your obligations to Mr.Soze.
此後你就c他刹幌嗲
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't kill you right now.
o好理由 教我F在不⒛
A gift from Mr.Soze.
@是 W先生o你的Y物
Good day, gentlemen.
再,先生
They got my whole life in here, everything I've done since I was 18.
他知我以前的一切 由我十八q以後所作的一切
They fuckin' know everything.
他什N都知道
Everybody I've ever worked with or did time with.
甚至知道以前曾c 我一同做牢的人
No.
不
- This isn't right. - I don't know.
-@事不 -我不知道
Who's that guy who used to talk about Soze in New York?
~s常提及 W的人是l?
- Bricks Marlin. - He did jobs for him, indirect stuff.
-是布e克R林 -他g接樗做事
He said he always made five times more money on it than the job was worth.
他常f他所做的事有五倍利
This guy's a pipe dream.
那人是幻想狂
Kobayashi's using him for window dressing.
彀脱潘够利用他作掩o
I don't know. This is bad.
我不知道,@糟透了
It's bullshit. This guy could be LAPD. It's a fuckin' setup.
都是鬼扯.@人可能是~sT警 @根本就是圈套
The way I hear it, Soze's some kind of butcher.
我f的 W是屠夫
- A peerless, psycho, fucked-up butcher. - There is no Keyser Soze!
-是Bo比的屠夫 -根本]有P W@人！
Who is Keyser Soze?
P W是l?
He's supposed to be Turkish. Some say his father was German.
他是土耳其人 有人f他父H是德人
Nobody ever believed he was real.
人人都J樗是的
Nobody knew him or saw anybody that ever worked directly for him.
]有人H眼^他
To hear Kobayashi tell it, anybody could have worked for Soze.
彀脱潘够f,任何人均可能 Wu命
You never knew. That was his power.
o人知道 那是他害之
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled...was convincing the world he didn't exist.
最巧妙是其令人相信他不存在
One story the guys told me, the story I believe
那些砘锔嬖V我一故事
...was from his days in Turkey.
我想那是他在土耳其rl生的事
There was a gang of Hungarians that wanted their own mob.
有班匈牙利人想收h徒
They realized that to be in power, you didn't need guns...
他知道想碛嗔Α
...or money or even numbers.
…不用械,金X, 甚至不需要手下
You just needed the will to do what the other guy wouldn't.
你只需做其他人不敢做的事
After a while they come into power, and then they come after Soze.
不久,他努力坐大 成H次於 W的另一大萘
He was small-time then. Just running dope, they say.
他r萘Σ淮,只是I毒品
They come to his home...in the afternoon looking for his business.
一天下午,他JM他家 想要找他麻
They find his wife and kids in the house, and decide to wait for Soze.
但只在家e找到他妻 於是Q定等 W回
He comes home to find his wife raped and children screaming.
W回家妻子被奸 孩子在哭喊
The Hungarians knew Soze was tough, not to be trifled with.
匈牙利人知道 W硬 都不敢惹他
They let him know they meant business.
他告V他只是想生意
No!
不！
They tell him they want his territory, all his business.
他f想要他的地P, 以及他所有I
Soze looks over the faces of his family.
Wh家人的
Then he showed these men of will what will really was.
然後向@班人以色
He tells them he would rather see his family dead...
他f他情看著家人死去…
...than live another day after this.
比屈辱求存好得多
He lets the last Hungarian go...
他放走最後那匈牙利人…
...waits until his family is in the ground, and goes after the rest of the mob.
等安葬了妻横, 然後找@班h徒逐一
He kills their kids, he kills their wives...
他⒘怂的孩子, ⒘怂的妻子…
...he kills their parents and their friends.
…⒘怂的父母及其朋友
He burns down the houses they live in...
掉他的居所…
...and the stores they work in.
…及他工作的店
He kills people that owe them money. And like that...
甚至⒛切┣匪X的人…
...he's gone, underground.
…然後就消失了
Nobody's ever seen him since. He becomes a myth.
自此再]人^他 他成了一神
A spook story that criminals tell their kids at night.
一罪犯晚上o孩子f的故事
"Rat on your pop, and Keyser Soze will get you."
“要是不, P W就碜ツ恪
No one ever really believes.
]有人相信@事
Do you believe in him?
你相信有@人?
Keaton always said:
基D是f:
"I don't believe in God, but I'm afraid of him."
“我不信上帝,但我怕他”
I believe in God.
我信上帝
And the only thing that scares me is Keyser Soze.
唯一我恐值木褪P W
You give any weight to this?
你Υ擞泻慰捶?
I can introduce you to Dan Metzheiser from Justice.
我o你介B法院的丹曼厮固
He's got a file on Soze in DC. It's been a hobby of his for a while.
他有些P於 W在A盛D的Y料 收集那砘锏馁Y料 缀醭闪怂的IN酆
A lot of guys equate him to that reporter on The Incredible Hulk.
大多等艘他 中的那者
You've heard of him?
你^他的事?
Where? On the street?
哪?在街上?
A few times. You know, outside stuff.
^状,都是oP痛W的事
Someone working for a guy who worked for a guy who got money from Soze.
有些人g接 W工作, K得了些X
Shit like that.
就是那
It could be an old badge. A hex sign.
那像是N古老的象徵, 一N魔印
Keep people from fucking with you when a name meant something.
@名字就是榱俗人躲的hh的
- But you're here. - Shit, yeah.
-但你已插手@事 -]e
This guy's trying to walk out of a hospital because he's so afraid of Soze.
@砘镆楹ε W, 甚至想尼t院e逃走
I'll run it up the flagpole.
我提高警X的
I came clean. I told it like it happened.
我是清白的,我已f了船上的事
So what about how I got there?
再f去那旱倪^程又有何用?
It's so full of holes, the DA would've told me to forget amnesty.
地方z察官也曾威{我e指望特赦
You got what you wanted out of me. Big deal.
你奈疑砩系玫搅讼胍的情 已了
- That's why you never told the DA? - You tell me.
-楹]把@些情r向地方z察官坦白? -那N你和我f…
If I told you the Loch Ness monster hired me, what would you say?
如果我向你f是尼斯湖怪雇的我, 你怎N想?
Turn state's evidence. We'll put you on the stand.
推翻C供,我召你作C
I've got immunity. What can you possibly offer me?
我已@了 你能o我_什Nl件?
If there really is a Keyser Soze, he's gonna come lookin' for you.
若真有P W其人, 他碚夷愕
Where's your head?
你有]有大X?
Where do you think the pressure is?
你以槭虑榫湍屈N?
Keyser Soze, or whatever you call him, knows where I am right now.
o你Q呼他P W或是什N, 他知道我身在何
He has the burner on your ass to let me go so he can scoop me up 10 minutes later.
他能在十分e就把我找出, 然後逼你放人
Immunity was just a deal with you assholes.
特赦也就是你@些混蛋想出淼
I got a new problem when I post bail.
若我被假,我就有了新麻
Why play into his hands? We can protect you.
楹巫他玩弄於股掌之g? 我能保o你
Thanks, Dave. Bang-up job so far. Extortion, coercion.
多x了,大l.你f的太勇了
Pardon me if I ask you to kiss my pucker.
若我要f出不敬的也e怪我
The same fuckers that rounded us up are now bailing me out?
把我s至F途末路的人 居然f要保o我?
Fuck you.
去你的
You think you can catch Keyser Soze?
你以槟隳艽住P W?
You think a guy like that comes this close to getting caught...and sticks his head out?
你以橄袼@拥娜引i待捕
If he comes up for anything, it'll be to get rid of me.
若他真要出F,那就是榱顺掉我
After that...
然後…
...my guess is you'll never hear from him again.
…我想你再也不到他的消息
What happened next?
後碓恿?
We woke up the next morning and Fenster was gone.
翌日醒,斯特已走了
He couldn't handle the idea of slumming for Soze.
他不想 Wu命
He left us a note wishing us good luck...
他留下字l祝我好\…
...and took a chunk of the money we'd scraped together.
…拿走了我淼乃有X
Then what?
然後怎?
McManus was furious.
克R{斯很怒
He talked about tracking him down and ripping his heart out. All sorts of shit.
f要把他捉回矶缢樗的心肝
That night, we got the call.
那晚我接到一
What call?
什N?
Kobayashi told us where we could find Fenster.
彀脱潘够f已找到了斯特
Let's get the fuck out of here.
我快x_@
We gotta bury him.
我得先把他埋了
With what?
用什N挖坑?
With our hands.
用我的手
This is nuts.
神病
It's dry fucking sand.
@e全是稚
When he rots the surfers are gonna smell him a mile away.
等他粕砀r 一e外的jW者也能到瞥
- Dig, you fuck. - What are we gonna do?
-o我挖 -我怎Nk?
This fuckin' guy is gonna kill us.
@砘锵氚盐全至
I don't know about you, peg leg, but I can run. I got no problem with that.
我不知道你的打算,拐_, 但我要跑路,我]什N}
Kobayashi doesn't seem to have a problem with it either.
彀脱潘够要值裟阋]什N}
You run, and we're gonna be diggin' a hole for you.
你就走吧, 我槟阃诹硪坑
You got that?
明白?
This ain't my boy we're burying. I don't owe anybody!
死的又不是我H鹤 我不欠任何人的！
- So fuck you. - He was my partner for five years.
-去你的吧 -我在一起混了五年
We did more jobs and I saw more money than you can ever count.
所^的X比你想像的多
So fuck you!
你o我去死！
- 'Cause now it's payback! - It's not payback!
-所以F在才要！ -@不是！
It's precaution.
@只是警告
You want payback? You wanna run? I don't care.
想那就去,想跑路的就跑吧 我不在乎
I'm not doin' this for Fenster.
我不是楣斯特@N做
I'm not doin' it for you.
也不是槟@N做
I'm doin' this for me.
我只是榱宋易约憾已
I'm gonna finish this thing.
我得把事情全了Y
This Kobayashi bastard is not gonna stand on me.
我不@叫彀脱潘够的s碎活下去
After they killed Fenster, nobody would run?
斯特被⑨,]有人逃跑?
- I wanted to. I thought we could make it. - Why didn't you say anything?
-我想的,我知道我定能逃 -那你槭颤N不f什N?
Believe me, I tried, but Keaton wouldn't have it.
相信我,我了, 但基D不同意@N做
It was too far-fetched for him.
我很y穹他
Keaton was a grounded guy. An ex-cop.
基D很固,他曾是T警
To a cop, the explanation is never that complicated.
T警是不接受}s的解的
It's always simple.
是容易受_
There's no mystery to the street, no arch-criminal.
不信街上的流言, 不信幕後有黑手
You got a body and think his brother did it, you're probably right.
看到一就是二
Nobody argued with Keaton.
]人c基D
They just set their minds to whacking Kobayashi.
人人都浜煤玫慕逃彀脱潘够
They're coming up.
他上砹
- Did you hear me? He's coming up. - He's on his way down.
-收到了?他上砹 -他正下
Don't move.
e
Press 20. Do it now.
按二十,快
Move.
出去
- The answer is "no." - Mr.Soze will be most--
-我的答覆是“不行” - W先生很--
Listen, cocksucker, there is no Keyser Soze.
著,混蛋 根本]有P W@人
Mention his name again, I'll kill you right now.
要再提@名字,我就立R⒘四
A strange threat. I assume you've come here to kill me anyway.
真是奇怪, 我以槟是榱⑽叶
We know that you can get to us...
我知道你找的到我…
...but now you know that we can get to you.
…可F在你也知道了 我能找到你
I'm giving you one last chance to call this off.
我最後o你次C去K止此事
My employer has made up his mind.
我的雇主已Q定了
- He does not change it. - Neither do we.
-他不改主意的 -我也不
You got Fenster, but you won't be able to get all of us.
你能⒐斯特, 但你⒉涣宋所有人
Not before one of us gets through to you.
至少在我中的某值裟阒前不
I believe you. I most sincerely do.
我信你的,是真的相信
You would not have been chosen were you not so suitable.
若你不是有能耐的人, 就不被xM
But I cannot make this decision. Whatever you threaten me with is...
但我不能做@Q定 o你怎印
...ludicrous in comparison to what will be done to me...
…恐我都於事oa
...if I do not carry out my orders in full.
…因我必完全绦忻令
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
想⒛愕娜司褪俏
I just wanted you to know that.
我只想你知道那c
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
I implore you, believe me...
就是我在┣,相信我
...Mr.Soze is very real...
… W先生_有其人
- ...and very determined. - We'll see.
-…而他是很Q的人 -我等著瞧吧
Before you do me in...
在你值粑抑前…
...you will let me finish my business with Miss Finneran first, won't you?
…允S我先去了Y c菲娜琳小姐的公事好?
What did you say?
你f什N?
Edie Finneran.
伊迪菲娜琳
She's upstairs in my office...
她正在巧衔业霓k公室…
...for an extradition deposition.
…等著交涉一兑渡案
I requested she be put on the case personally.
她要求我H自c她@案子
She flew in yesterday.
她是昨天w砺迳即的
No matter.
]PS
Kill away.
邮职
You're lying.
你在fe
Am I?
有?
Miss Finneran's escort while she's here in Los Angeles.
菲娜琳小姐在洛杉期g ⑹艿胶芎玫谋Ｗo
Never leaves her for a moment.
保S片刻不x其左右
I thought you'd be glad to know she's in good hands.
我想你也高d 她的安全受到保障
Get some rest. The boat will be ready for you on Friday.
好好休息去吧 船在星期五到
If I see you or any of your friends before then...
若你或你的朋友 有任何pe妄
...Miss Finneran will be the victim of a most gruesome violation before she dies.
…菲娜琳小姐受折磨而死
As indeed will your father, Mr.Hockney...
哈肯尼先生,你的父H…
...and your Uncle Randall in Arizona, Mr.Kint.
…有肯特先生在 e桑那州的叔叔也如此
I might only castrate Mr.McManus' nephew, David.
我H手掉 克R{斯先生的侄子
Do I make myself clear?
你都清楚了?
We will take care of the two bodies downstairs.
我理窍履删企w
We'll add them to the cost of Mr.Fenster.
K把那~算到范斯特先生身上
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
恕失陪,各位
It's a logistical nightmare.
@真是龉之的
Close quarters. 10, maybe 20 men.
s有十到二十人
There's no tellin' how many more are gonna be below deck.
我估不到船冗有多少人
Can we stealth these guys?
要偷u那些砘?
With all that coke, they're gonna be ready.
因槭嵌酒方灰, 他小心防的
Which brings me to sunny point Number 2.
而且Ыo我另一}
Even if one of us gets through and jacks the boat, we still got nothin'.
即使我偷u成功K劫走那船 亦一o所得
What if we wait for the money?
等他收了X又如何?
Ten more men at least.
那至少要再多值羰人
In my opinion, it can't be done.
以我看,@行不通
Anyone who goes in is not comin' out alive.
lM去了都不活著出
- I'm gonna wait for the money. - Me, too.
-我等X到再下手 -我也是
- Did you hear what he just said? - If I'm goin' in, I want a cut.
-你有他在f? -既然M去了,就]指望全身而退
Me, too.
我也是
There's nothing that can't be done.
天下]有k不成的事
I just can't believe we're gonna walk in to certain death.
我直不敢相信, 我就@N去送死
The news said it's raining in New York.
_ef~s正在下雨
What language is that?
他f的那是什N?
I don't know. Russian, I think.
不知道,可能是俄Z
Hungarian?
好象是匈牙利Z
The package has arrived, gentlemen.
各位,包裹已送到了
You kids ready?
你浜昧?
I would be if I didn't have to stop and answer you.
若不是停下泶鹉 就已A浜昧
I'm ready.
我已渫桩
McManus, you better be set up in 10 seconds.
克R{斯,你要在十秒雀愣
I want you to stay here.
我要你留在@e
I'm supposed to cover--
我本硪掩o--
If we don't get out of this, take the money and go.
如果我出不砹, 上Xs快走
I can't--
我不能--
Find Edie. Tell her everything that happened.
去找伊迪 告V她全部真相
She knows people. She knows what to do.
她JRS多人 她知道如何理
If I don't get Kobayashi my way, she'll get him her way.
如果用我的方法除不掉彀脱潘够, 那N她有e的k法
- What if I-- - Just do what I say.
-可要是我-- -按我f的去做
Please.
拜了
Tell her that...
告V她….
Tell her I tried.
告V她我已M力了
McManus, he's on his way.
克R{斯,他^砹
I'm there.
我已就位
One, two, three, four...
?二,三,四…
...five, six, seven...
…五,六,七…
Oswald was a fag.
W斯瓦德的活不好职
Hi.
你好
How you doin'?
你好?
Is there a problem?
有什N}?
Now.
快
"Old McDonald had a farm
王二先生有K地
"Ee-aye, ee-aye, O
伊呀,伊呀,
"And on that farm, he shot some guys"
“在那地e他⒘税嗳恕
Elvis has left the building.
明星要出隽
Hold fire. Hold fire. Vamonos!
e_,e_.自己人
Hello.
好啊
Why didn't you run?
你楹尾惶?
I froze up.
我被呆了
I thought about Fenster and how he looked when we buried him.
我想起了斯特被埋葬r的幼
Then I thought about Keaton, and it looked like he might pull it off.
然後我又想到基D, 那r候看起硭x成功不h
A boy found a body on the beach today.
有男孩在沙┥习lF一具企w
Thrown clear of the boat. Shot twice in the head.
是被人拇上下海的 ^部中了
Two guys from the Bureau identified him.
事物局的人去b定了他的身份
- What else? - His name was Arturo Marquez.
-然後呢? -他叫阿D_ R克
A petty smuggler from Argentina.
是阿根廷走私犯
He was arrested last year in New York for trafficking.
去年在~s曾因走私而被捕
He escapes to California. They pick him up in Long Beach.
他逃往加州,但在Lu被捉回
They're setting up extradition, he escapes again.
他安排引渡他回 但又被他逃
Now, get this.
看看@
Edie Finneran's brought in to advise on the proceedings.
伊迪菲娜琳提出的引渡建h
New York faxed me a copy of his testimony.
~s鹘o了我一份 R克C供的影本
- He was a rat. - A big fucking rat.
-他是告密者 -是大叛徒
Arturo was very opposed to returning to prison.
阿D_ 很害怕回到Oz
So much so, that he named close to 50 people.
甚至於他供出了⒔五十人
Guess who he named in the finale.
猜猜最後的人名是l?
There's more.
有
I'll tell you what I know. Stop me when this sounds familiar.
我把所知一切告V你 若f重覆了就告V我
There was no dope on that boat.
船上根本就]有毒品
You, stay quiet.
待著e出音
He's here.
他砹
I know he's here. That's him. I'm telling you, that's him.
我知道他砹,就是他 我告V你,就是他
I know he's here!
我知道他砹耍
- You can't understand. That's him. - Shut up.
-你不明白.是他 -安o
That's him. You hear me? I'm telling you, it's Keyser Soze!
就是他,你到]? 我告V你,是P W砹耍
- Where's Hockney? - I don't know.
-哈肯尼在哪e? -我不知道
There's no coke.
@]毒品
- What? - You heard me, dumb fuck.
-什N? -你得很清楚,死的
- There's no coke! - What the fuck? No coke?
-根本就]有毒品！ -你到底什N意思?]有毒品?
I've been up and down in every fucking room.
我已仔搜^了每g房
- There's gotta be coke! - There is nothing!
-一定有的！ -根本]有！
Nothing!
]有！
Don't you fuck with me.
e跟我_玩笑了
There is no fucking coke!
根本就]有毒品！
I'm out of here.
我要走了
I told them nothing.
我什N都]λf
I swear.
我l誓我]有
I told them nothing. Please.
我什N也]f,求你了
What the fuck is goin' on?
究竟是怎N回事?
The strangest thing.
@是真是太怪了
That's what you said. You saw a man in a suit with a slim build.
那就是你供~中所提到^的 那穿西服的瘦男人?
Wait a minute.
等等
Are you saying you saw Keyser Soze?
你f你看了P W?
- You said you didn't know who it was. - I know there was dope on that boat.
-先前的C供e你f不知道那男人是l -我知道船上肯定有毒品
- Stop stallin'. - I'm not.
-e再拖延rg -我]有
- You know what I'm getting at. - Get out of my face.
-你明白我想知道什N -o我走_
I got immunity. I don't have to take this.
我已被豁免了 不需要再受你恐
You know what I'm getting at.
你明白我想知道什N
- I don't know what you're talking about. - The truth!
-我不知道你在f什N -f出真相！
Try to tell me you saw someone kill Keaton.
告V我是l⒘嘶D
I did.
我f了
You're lying to me.
你在撒e
- You've known this whole time. - I don't know what you're saying.
-你知道事真相 -我不知道你在f什N
I did see Keaton get shot. I swear to you.
我看基D中了,我l誓
Why didn't you help him? You had a gun.
你楹尾痪人?你手上有
He was your friend.
他可是你的朋友
Because I was afraid.
因槲液ε
- Afraid. - Afraid of what?
-怕O了 -你怕什N?
- Afraid of-- - I knew it was Keyser Soze.
-怕什N-- -我知道那是P W
It was Keyser Soze, I mean, the Devil himself.
是P W,他是魔鬼的化身
How do you shoot the Devil in the back?
你怎N敢在魔鬼的背後_?
What if you miss?
要是射不中又如何?
Let's get back to the pier.
那f回a^的事
- Arturo Marquez. Ever hear of him? - What? No.
-f^阿D_ R克? -l?]有
He was a stool pigeon for the Justice Department.
他是司法部的人
He swore out a statement to federal marshals...
他向邦绦泄黉了份口供
...saying that he had seen and could positively identify one...
…f他^K能J出…
It says right here in the report.
@蟾嬷羞d著
He had intimate knowledge of his businesses, including...
他熟知P商K一切I铡
...but not exclusive to, drug trafficking and murder.
包括\毒及\⒁酝獾氖虑
I never heard of him.
我奈绰f^他
His own people were selling him to a gang of Hungarians.
他的手下把他出uo匈牙利h
Most likely the same Hungarians that Soze all but wiped out back in Turkey.
@班匈牙利人似乎 被 W清除Ks回土耳其
The money wasn't there for dope.
那XK不是用碣I毒品的
The Hungarians were going to buy the one guy...
@班匈牙利人收I…
...that could incriminate Keyser Soze.
一能把P W治罪的人
- I said I never heard of him. - But Keaton did.
-我f了我奈绰^他 -但基D^
Edie Finneran was Marquez's extradition advisor.
伊迪菲娜琳是R克引渡案的
She knew who he was and what he knew.
她知道他是l,知道他掌握的Y料
There were no drugs on that boat. It was a hit.
船上根本]有毒品 @只是次\⑿
A suicide mission to whack out the one guy...
@次自⑹降男
...that could finger Keyser Soze.
…目的是去值暨@ 能指CP W的砘
So Soze put some thieves to it...
於是 W派了班\去绦
...men he knew he could march into certain death.
他算好了@班人一定死
You're saying Soze sent us to kill someone?
你f W利用我去⑷?
I'm saying Keaton did. He left you behind for a reason.
我f就是基D本人, 他把你留在後面是有原因的
Just do what I tell you.
按我f的去做
If you all knew that Soze could find you anywhere...
既然o跑到何,  W都能找到你…
...why did he give you the money to run?
…楹芜o你金X逃亡?
- He could have used you on the boat. - He wanted me to live.
-他可以在船上就把你值 -他不想我死
A one-time dirty cop without a loyalty in the world...
一^去的污T警
...finds it in his heart to save a worthless rat cripple?
…竟然有w挽救跛子\的善心?
No, sir. Why?
@不可能,先生 你能o我理由?
Edie.
是因橐恋
I don't buy that reform story for a minute.
我念^到尾就不信 @改^自新的故事
Even if I did...
就算我信@c…
...I certainly don't believe he would send you to protect her.
…我也不相信他派你去保o她
So why?
o我解?
Because he was my friend.
因槲是朋友
No, he wasn't your friend. Keaton didn't have friends.
不,他不是你的朋友 基D]有任何朋友
What are you doing here?
你磉@质颤N?
He saved you because he wanted it that way.
他留下你的命 是因樗用的到你
It was his will.
@就是他的目的
- Keaton was Keyser Soze. - No.
-基D就是P W -不是
A man who could wrangle the wills of men like Hockney and McManus.
只有他才能值 哈肯尼和克R{斯@角色
A man who could engineer a police lineup...through all his years of contacts in NYPD.
只有他才能p的 在警局e安排指J
The kind of man who could've killed Edie Finneran.
只有他才忍的⒑σ恋戏颇攘
She was found yesterday at a hotel in Pennsylvania...
她的企w昨日在 e夕法尼州一g酒店被lF
...shot twice in the head.
…^部B中而亡
What do you think about Keaton now?
F在你基D有何看法?
Edie?
伊迪死了?
He used all of you to get him on that boat.
他利用你掩o他上船
He couldn't get on alone. He had to pull the trigger himself...
@事他本硪人做不了, 他必要H自下手…
...to make sure he got his man...
…以_J值袅四…
...the one man that could identify him.
…能指J他的砘
This is all bullshit.
全是胡f
You said you saw him die.
你fH眼看他死了
Or did you?
肯定?
You had to hide when you heard the police cars.
到警淼r,你想藏起
You said you heard the shot before the fire...
你f在起火前到…
...but you didn't see him die.
…可你]看他死
- I knew him. He would never-- - He programmed you.
-我t解他,他^不-- -他是在利用你
He programmed you to tell us what he wanted you to.
他安排由你碚f整_局
He knew we were close. You said it yourself.
就如你f的, 他知道我不出什N
Where was the political pressure to protect you from?
保你出去的政治毫τ珊味?
It was Keaton.
就是基D在幕後
- Immunity was your reward. - But why me?
-被豁免就是o你的p -但槭颤N偏偏是我?
Why not Fenster or McManus or Hockney?
槭颤N不挑斯特, 或是克R{斯和哈肯尼?
Why me? I'm stupid. I'm a cripple. Why me?
槭颤N是我? 我又蠢又跛,槭颤N是我?
Because you're a cripple.
就因槟闶跛子
Because you're stupid.
就因槟愫苡薮
Because you're weaker than them.
就因槟惚人]用
If he's dead...
要是他死了….
If what you say is true, then it won't matter.
要是你f的是真的, 那N就]}了
It was his idea to hit the taxi service, wasn't it?
u艟是不是他的主意?
- Come on, tell me the truth. - It was all Keaton.
-ξ艺f -是基D提出的
We followed him from the beginning.
我一直跟著他
I didn't know.
我不知道
I saw him die.
我看到他死了
I believe he's dead. Christ.
我也相信他已死了
You're not safe on your own.
你为一人不安全
You think he's...
你J樗是….
I don't know.
我不知道
Keyser Soze's a shield, or like you said, a spook story.
P W只是化名, 或就如你f的,是髡f
But I know Keaton, and someone is out there pulling strings for you.
但我很t解基D, 你一出去就有人等著值裟
- Stay here and let us protect you. - I'm not bait. I post today.
-e出去,我保o你 -我才不TD,我已自由了
You posted 20 minutes ago.
二十分前你就可以走了
Capt. Leo wants you out of here.
eWL想你快x_@e
- Unless you turn state's. - I'll take my chances.
-除非你想翻供 -我把握C的,x了
If someone wants to get you, they're gonna get you out there.
如果有人想要值裟, 那他一定要x在外面下手
Turn state's evidence. You might never see trial.
若你改口供,就再也不用害怕
Maybe so.
也S如此
But I'm not a rat.
可我不是叛徒
Fuckin' cops.
死的l子
Excuse me, can I use your fax machine?
能借用你的髡C?
You'll have to sign for these, Mr.Kint.
在@汉名,肯特先生
One watch, gold.
一K金表
One cigarette lighter, gold.
金打火C
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
一包,xx
We still got nothing.
我仍是一o所知
I know what I wanted to know about Keaton.
我知道了P於基D的事
Which is nothing.
那毫or值
No matter. He'll have to know how close we came.
]PS,他很快知道 我t解了多少
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze...
不管P W存不存在
...if Keaton is alive, he's not comin' up again.
…只要基D活著, 他就不再出F了
I'll find him.
我去找他
Waste of time.
那是浪Mrg
A rumor's not a rumor that doesn't die.
若是髀不平息, 那就不算是髀了
What?
什N?
Nothing.
]什N
Man, you're a slob.
夥,你@赫y的
But it all has a system.
但|西[放的都有律
It all makes sense if you look at it right. You gotta stand back from it.
要是全[的整整RR的, 就]有H和力了
You wanna see a real horror show? See my garage.
要看更恐怖的地方? 到我烊ゾ椭道了
Convince me. Tell me every last...
f服我,告V我每
When I was in that barbershop quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
我曾加入^在伊利Z州邵崎市 的一男四重唱M合…
- Where's your head? - We need to think, think back.
-你到底有]有大X? -我需要先思考周全,再想想
I'm sure you've heard tall tales.
我肯定你已^不少餮
- Bricks Marlin. - This isn't right.
-是布e克R林 -@事不
- I just wanna hear your story. - It's all there.
-我想你的故事 -已全f了
- I'm tellin' it straight. - Some guy in California called Redfoot.
-我f的都是 -碜约又莸,名叫雷德福特
- A gift from Mr.Soze. - Talk to me.
-@是 W先生送上的Y物 -老ξ艺f
- What about Redfoot? - Mr.Redfoot knew nothing.
-那雷德福特呢? -雷德福特先生K不知情
- Using pawns... - A big fat guy. Like, orca fat.
-利用不知情的人… -是超大胖子
There was a lawyer...
有律…
Kobayashi...
叫 彀脱潘够
When I was picking beans in Guatemala we made fresh coffee.
我曾在瓜地R拉L^ 咖啡豆磨的新r咖啡
- I know you thought he was a good man. - I know he was good.
-我知道你J樗是好人 -我知道他很好
- You tell me every last detail. - The strangest thing.
-告V我全部的 -@事怪O了
How do you shoot the Devil in the back?
你怎N敢在魔鬼的背後_?
This guy is protected from up on high by the Prince of...
@砘锏尼崤_很硬
What's your story, pretzel man?
ff你的故事,拐_佬
- There was a lawyer. - What lawyer?
-有律 -什N律?
I am Mr.Kobayashi.
我就是彀脱潘够
- Kobayashi. Kobayashi. - Tell me every last detail.
-彀脱潘够,彀脱潘够, -告V我所有的
- I work for Keyser Soze. - Convince me. Convince me.
-我P W做事, -f服我,f服我
Every creep and scumbag that works the street...
所有犯罪的大小角色
...will know the name of Verbal Kint.
…都知道S伯肯特的大名
The cripple, did you see him?
你^那跛子?
- The cripple! Which way did he go? - He went out that way.
-那跛子！他朝那e走了? -他往那去了
I know you know something. I know you're not telling...
我知道你知情, 我知道你]f…
I'm smarter than you...
我比你明
...and I'm gonna find out whether you like it or not.
…不管你是否意, 我都找到我要的答案
To a cop, the explanation is never complicated.
T警是不接受}s的解的
- It's always simple. - The truth!
-是那N容易受_ -真相
There's no arch-criminal behind it all.
根本就]什N幕手主使
Somebody with power, somebody who is capable...
那人有@能力,能蛘莆铡
You think a guy like that gets this close to getting caught...and sticks his head out?
你以橄袼@拥娜引i待捕?
Because you're stupid. Because you're a cripple.
就是因槟阌薮,就因槟闶酋俗
What I wanna know is, who's the gimp?
F在我想知道那跛子是l?
You've known the whole fuckin' time.
你完全知道事真相
If he comes up for anything it'll be for me. I'm sure Keaton is dead.
要是他硪彩且找我, 我肯定基D已死了
I can't feel my legs, Keyser.
我的p腿]有知X,P
First thing I learned on the job. You know what?
诌@行我W的 第一件事知道是什N?
- How to spot a murderer. - You got the cripple in there?
-就是如何辨J词 -你到那跛子了?
- Did he mention Keyser Soze? - Who?
-他有提到P W? -l?
After that...
那之後…
...my guess is you'll never hear from him again.
…我猜之後再不到他的消息
The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled...was convincing the world he didn't exist.
最巧妙乃令人相信他不存在
And like that...
然後就象那印
...he's gone
…消失的o影o